# **Arnold Jin**

## **FULL-STACK / E-Commerce DEVELOPER**

Gmail: arnoldjin0712@gmail.com, Telegram: @greenland712, Skype: live:.cid.9e2f3680ddbc5cb5

Skilled and motivated full-stack developer with 6+ years of experience.

Created 40+ websites using several programming languages and frameworks. Advanced in many languages and frameworks such as JavaScript/Typescript, React/Next/Vue, and Ruby on Rails.

Built 10+ E-Commerce websites using Shopify, Magento, and Headless CMS (Strapi, Contentful).

Own the development of product features end-to-end including scoping, architecting, coding, testing, and rolling out features.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Aug 2022 - Present

## Full-stack Developer, Self-Employed

- Improved eCommerce web app performance by +18% using ImageEngine for React and reduced response time from 8.21s to fewer 3s and made real-time chats secure u sing SSL by NextJS
- Created a Map Tracking System and data analysis charts and diagrams for Uber-like platform using React, TailwindCSS, react-leaflet, chart.js and D3.js.
- Developed highly interactive web applications while integrating Restful APIs and external web services, ensuring high performance.
- Built 4 customized node.js modules integrated with social APIs and deployed projects by AWS EC2, CloudFormation, and Jenkins

## Aug 2019 – Aug 2022 Full-stack Developer, C&F

- Implemented features for the main site and internal applications using React/Redux , NextJS, NodeJS with GraphQL.
- Improved and upgraded the development tooling and workflow for several projects (Ruby on Rails).
- Integrated platforms with various cloud services and third-party APIs, including Amazon S3, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, PayPal and Mongo Cluster.

- Built E-Commerce website using NextJS and Strapi and deployed it by DigitalOcean.
- Built Swagger API to help users build, document, test, and consume RESTful web ser vices
- Established reusable & responsive React chart components using D3.js that support interactive visualizations of data and analysis.
- Used Elastic search engine on AWS to speed up web page performance and React Hooks to prevent unnecessary re-renders.

# Nov 2016 – July 2019 Front-end Developer, ANGI

- Supported the hosting and management of a client base of 300+ websites.
- Created a web app MVP for a store delivery management platform with 200+ business customers to create, manage, and monitor deliveries using React and Redux.
- Added features to meditation app with 5,000+ monthly users, enabling audio and video uploads using Amazon S3 bucket.
- Introduced new media to the company's production team.

## **EDUCATION**

## Warsaw University of Technology, Poland

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science 2012 - 2016

## **SKILLS**

## Languages

- Ruby
- JavaScript/TypeScript
- Python
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5

#### Frameworks & Libraries

- Ruby on Rails
- Node.js
- React/Redux
- Vue.js
- Next.js, Nuxt.js

• Django/Flask

## **Database**

- MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- MongoDB, Oracle, Amazon DynamoDB
- Firebase

## **AWS & E-Commerce Tools & CMS**

- AWS Lamda, AWS S3, AWS EC2
- Shopify, Magento, Strapi
- Salesforce, SFCC, SFSC, Salesforce CRM, API2Cart

## **Paradigms & Tools**

- Scrum, Agile
- CI/CD
- SOLID, DRY, KISS
- Unit Testing, TDD
- Jira/BitBucket, Github, ClickUp
- Postman